discogs.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy Policy – Discogs

View Discogs Privacy Policy effective through December 31, 2019

View NearMint Privacy Policy effective through December 31, 2019

\-------

_Effective Date: January 1, 2020_

Your privacy and protection of Your data is important to Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs) and our affiliates (“We”, “Our”, “Us” or “Discogs”) and this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) represents Our commitment to care for Your “personal information” (or similar terms to describe the data about you as defined by various domestic international regulations). This Policy applies to the personal information We collect, use, disclose, and sell via Our websites, [discogs.com](https://www.discogs.com/) and [nearmint.io](https://nearmint.io/), applications, and through any associated service, including Application Program Interfaces (“APIs”), (collectively, the “Service”). 

This Policy does not apply to personal information collected by or through any other online or offline sites, products, or services. When You use third party sites, products, or services, You are subject to those third parties’ policies. In addition, this Policy does not cover personal information You independently disclose to other users of the Service. Disclosure of personal information to buyers, sellers, contributors, or other users (collectively, “Other Users”) outside of disclosure to Us should be discussed with those Other Users prior to providing such information.  We are not responsible for the privacy or data protection processes of any Other Users of Our Service.

By using Our Service, You confirm that you have read and agree to abide by the terms of this Policy, Our [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service), and other applicable policies found on Our Service.  You acknowledge that We will process Your information in the United States, the Netherlands, Japan and any other country where We or Our service providers/processors operate. If You withdraw Your consent to this Policy (by closing Your account, if any, and/or disabling cookies), then You may not have access to certain portions of the Service, including the benefits of membership, buying and selling options, language preferences, etc. In certain cases, We may continue to process Your personal information, but only if We have a legal basis to do so.

We encourage You to review the entire Policy.  For quick access to a particular Policy section, click on the desired link below: 

GENERAL PRIVACY AND DATA PROTECTION INFORMATION

INFORMATION COLLECTED

INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

RETENTION AND STORAGE

SAFEGUARDING YOUR INFORMATION

TRANSFER OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

PERSONALLY-IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION SUBMITTED BY CHILDREN

CALIFORNIA DISCLOSURES

NOTIFICATION AND OTHER PRIVACY PREFERENCES

PUBLIC GROUPS & FORUMS

ANALYTICS & DISPLAY ADVERTISING, COOKIES

YOUR RIGHT TO ACCESS, ALTER, OR ERASE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

YOUR PORTABILITY RIGHTS

NON-DISCRIMINATION POLICY

COMPLAINTS

DISPUTE RESOLUTION

GENERAL

CONTACT US

## GENERAL PRIVACY AND DATA PROTECTION INFORMATION

**We are committed to complying with applicable privacy and data protection laws and regulations designed to protect your personal information, including, but not limited to, the General Data Protection Regulation and other applicable regional, national and state privacy and data protection laws and regulations worldwide as they become effective.**   **We comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework** as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. We have certified to the Department of Commerce that We adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view Our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). We are liable for privacy violations committed by third parties to which We provide Your information as limited by Our contractual agreements with those third parties. All personal information received from the EU and Switzerland will be subject to the Privacy Shield Principles. Additional details about the information We collect, the purpose of collection, Your rights, and how to contact us are provided in detail within this Policy.

_Data Controller_ : Personal information provided to Us in connection with the Service or otherwise is controlled and processed by Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403. Our EU representative is Discogs B.V., located at Korte Leidsedwarsstraat 12, 1017 RC Amsterdam, the Netherlands.  Our privacy team can be contacted at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.

_Data Protection Officer_ : Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

## INFORMATION COLLECTED

We practice privacy by design and only collect and process that information which is necessary to provide the Service or meet Our legitimate business needs.  Generally, We collect the following categories of personal information from Service users:

Category of Information

| 

Description

| 

Source of Information

| 

Purpose

| 

Information Shared With  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Identity and Contact Information

| 

Identifiers such as a real name, alias, username, gravatar, postal address (shipping), unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, Session ID (SSID), email address, account name, or other similar identifiers, information submitted on webforms, and information contributed to forums.

Additional identifiers including identification number or beneficiary information as it relates to employee benefits and obligations.

| 

Consumer (User)

| 

To provide the Service, including account registration, buying, selling, contributing, etc.; When provided with a job application, it is used to consider Your employment with Us or, if employed, to provide benefits or comply with legal reporting obligations

| 

Operating Systems and platforms; Email service providers; Parties to a transaction (if using the marketplace); Job application information is not shared; Employee benefit information is shared with benefits providers and regulators, as applicable  
  
Commercial Information

| 

Records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies, or financial identifier (i.e., PayPal ID).

| 

Consumer (User)

| 

To provide the Service related to transactions

| 

Operating Systems and platforms; Email service providers; Parties to a transaction (if using the marketplace)  
  
Technical Information

| 

Internet or other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to, browsing history, search history, and information regarding Your interaction with the Service or marketing materials, operating systems and other technology used on Your devices to access the Service.

| 

Consumer (User); User Device

| 

To provide the Service, including personalization and performance/ analytics to improve the Service.

| 

Operating Systems and platforms  
  
Geolocation Information

| 

Non-precise geolocation data based on Your IP address or other analytics tools.

| 

Consumer (User); User Device

| 

To provide the Service, including personalization and targeted advertising

| 

Operating Systems and platforms

*Analytics and advertising networks (if You allow performance, targeting, or social media cookies - this constitutes a “sale” under California Consumer Privacy Act)  
  
Professional Information

| 

Prior work and other related information provided to Us if You apply for a job with Us

| 

Consumer (User)

| 

To consider Your employment with Us

| 

Not shared  
  
Educational Information

| 

Education information provided to Us if You apply for a job with Us

| 

Consumer (User)

| 

To consider Your employment with Us

| 

Not shared  
  
Inferred Information

| 

Inferences drawn from any of the information identified above reflecting the Your preferences, behavior, and interests.

| 

Consumer (User); User Device

| 

To provide the Service, including personalization and targeted advertising

| 

Operating Systems and platforms

*Analytics and advertising networks (if You allow performance, targeting, or social media cookies - this constitutes a “sale” under California Consumer Privacy Act)  
  
Browsing Information

| 

Browsing data collected via cookies, such as page URL or page metadata

| 

User Device

| 

To personalize targeted advertising

| 

Analytics and advertising networks (if You allow performance, targeting, or social media  cookies - this constitutes a “sale” under California Consumer Privacy Act)  
  
We do not collect information about users’ race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, health data, genetic data, biometric data, or any other protected classes of information. We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offenses unless such information is surfaced in a job application.

We obtain contact details and other personal information regarding media contacts and influencers from a variety of sources including Cision. If you wish to know more about how such information is collected and used, please refer to Cision’s privacy notice at [www.cision.com/us/legal/privacy-policy/](http://www.cision.com/us/legal/privacy-policy/). 

We rely on the following lawful bases to collect and process personal information based on the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and the California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”):

  * Consent: use for a specific purpose based on Your clear consent. (GDPR)
  * Contract: use to provide the Service to You pursuant to Our policies. (GDPR)
  * Legal: use is necessary for Us to comply with the law. (GDPR)
  * Legitimate interests: use is necessary for Our legitimate interests that is not overridden by Your personal information protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. (GDPR)
  * Business: use by Our or Our service provider’s/processor’s operational purposes that is reasonable and necessary to provide the Service (CCPA)
  * Commercial: use by Us to increase Our revenue, such as by encouraging transactions through the marketplace or user subscriptions to marketing-related emails. (CCPA) 

More specifically, Our basis for collecting and using the personal information described will depend on the portion(s) of the Service utilized:

**Service**

| 

**Personal Information Collected**

| 

**Purpose of Collection**

| 

**Basis for Use**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Browsing

| 

Cookie-based information related to browsing, Your device, and IP address.  Dependent on Your jurisdiction, cookies may only be placed with Your consent.

| 

Analytics (Service health, usability, etc.) and advertising (with consent, as applicable)

| 

Legitimate Interest;

Commercial purpose  
  
Registration for discogs.com and Discogs applications

| 

Username, email address, SSID, IP address, geolocation, browser type/version, and operating system

| 

Verification of Your identity when You access Our Service, fraud prevention, communication with You, and customization of certain aspects of Your visits, such as language.  Registration also allows You to list or purchase items for sale, contribute to the catalogue, and build a collection and wantlist.

| 

Contract; Legitimate Interest;

Business purpose  
  
Selling 

| 

Full name, address, PayPal Account Name, and VAT and ABN (where applicable)

| 

Use of the marketplace to engage in transactions with purchasers.

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Shipping Labels Service

| 

Address and phone number

| 

Population of shipping label(s) on Your behalf

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Discogs Payments

| 

1\. Depending on whether You are a business or individual: name, date of birth, email address, phone number, company name, tax identification number, bank account information, government issued photo identification, and bank statement or voided check.  

2\. Username, account creation date, IP address and email address 

| 

1\. Identity verification (per financial regulations) - this information is required by Our third party payment processor(s) as outlined in the [Discogs Payments Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360000114233-Discogs-Payments-Policy).

2\. Fraud review for accounts.

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Purchasing

| 

Full name, address, and phone number (optional) 

| 

To complete transaction shipping from seller.  We do not collect or store any purchaser payment information, such as credit card information. Such information is provided directly to the seller by the purchaser with no interaction by or through Us. Depending on Your payment option selection, certain third parties may have access to such information (i.e., PayPal, Inc., Stripe, Inc. or Adyen B.V.)

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Registration for bookogs, comicogs, filmogs, gearogs, posterogs, and vinylhub

| 

Username, email address, SSID ,IP address, geolocation, browser type/version, and operating system

| 

Verification of Your identity when You access Our Service, fraud prevention, communication with You, and customization of certain aspects of Your visits, such as language.  Registration also allows You to contribute to the catalogue, and build a collection, wantlist and other lists.

| 

Contract; Legitimate Interest;

Business purpose  
  
Discogs Self-Serve Advertising

| 

Name, email address, address, phone number, and company name

| 

Guest transactions.  Please see the [Discogs Self-Serve Advertising Payment Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360024763213-Discogs-Self-Serve-Advertising-Payment-Policy) for additional information.

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Registration for Crate Diggers

| 

Email address and country

| 

Communicate relevant information about upcoming, local events

| 

Contract; 

Business purpose  
  
Registration for NearMint

| 

Email address, name, address, username

| 

Inventory management service

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
Marketing Emails

| 

Email address

| 

You must sign up (opt in) to receive marketing-related emails.  If You have previously consented to receive newsletters or other commercial emails, then You may opt out in Your notification preferences or from within the email messages themselves.

| 

Consent;

Business purpose; Commercial purpose  
  
User Support

| 

Email address, username (if registered) and other information You provide for the purpose of responding to Your question or concern, including information submitted to Us to make a valid copyright claim, such as name and contact information.

| 

Reviewing Your questions/concerns and responding to You.  We ask that You do not submit any information to Us that is not absolutely necessary for Us to assist You.

| 

Contract;

Legal;

Business purpose  
  
Error Reporting

| 

Username, email address, IP address, device information

| 

Reviewing errors or issues with the Service reported by you directly

| 

Contract;

Business purpose  
  
_Cookies_ : We may use cookies and other technology to keep track of Your online interaction with Our site. Certain countries and regions (i.e., the EU) require that You provide consent for cookies that are not strictly necessary, which can be managed through Your “Cookie Settings” link on the Service in those locations.  

  * Performance cookies allow us to analyze how users use the Service and infer Your general location (country-level), preferences, interests, and online behavior to improve Our Service by providing more relevant content based on analytics results.
  * Targeting cookies allow us to target advertisements to You based on Your inferred location (country-level), preferences, interests, and online behavior.
  * Social media cookies are used to indicate a “like” or other action to content on social media. 

Cookies may also provide information to Us about Your online interaction with other sites and provide information to other sites about Your online interaction with Us. The collection and use of information by companies placing cookies is governed by the relevant company’s privacy policy and is not covered by this Policy. You have rights regarding Our use of cookies. Please see the[ Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for more information about Your cookie options.  We **do not** participate in any automated decision making, such as profiling (other than for cookie-based targeted marketing), with regards to the Service and Your personal information.

## INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

We share personal information with service providers (processors) that act as an agent to perform tasks on Our behalf and under Our instructions. Examples include providers that assist with payment processing (i.e., PayPal), shipping (i.e., USPS), or providers that We contract with to send emails on Our behalf (i.e., MailChimp). If You process payments through Discogs Payments, in the U.S., You will be contracting for this service directly with Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), and in the EU, You will be contracting for this service directly with Discogs B.V. sending emails on Our behalf, and fulfilling orders. In both cases, the payment processor working on Our behalf is Adyen B.V. This information is limited only to the information needed to perform the tasks.  If certain cookies are enabled on Your device, then We may also share cookie-related information with related service providers, such as analytics and advertising providers or social media companies. Additional information about the service providers/processors We use to support delivery of Our Service is set forth at [Processors List](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360004623634-Discogs-Processors).  For additional information about service provider (processor) and third party privacy practices, please review those partes’ privacy policies and notices.

We will provide You with notice in the event We intend to share Your information with a third party (other than as described above) or for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You. Prior to sharing such information, You will be provided with clear, conspicuous, and readily available mechanisms to opt in or out of such sharing, as required by applicable laws and regulations.  Except as described in this Policy, We **do not** otherwise share Your information with any third parties without Your consent.  We **do not** provide or sell email addresses or collection/wantlist information to any third party without Your consent.  Registered users can control the public availability of their collection/wantlist information in the account settings.  Please see “Notification and Other Privacy Preferences” below for additional information on limiting the sharing of Your information.

_Affiliates_ : We may share information with domestic and foreign affiliates controlling or controlled by Us, including Meta Zink Corporation, Discogs B.V., Discogs G.K., and NearMint, LLC, in order to provide the Service. Our affiliates are subject to the terms of this Policy and follow the same privacy practices as Us. Zink Media, LLC is the primary Data Controller for personal information collected and processed through Our and Our affiliates’ sites and services. All sharing is subject to the Privacy Shield frameworks noted above and an intercompany data processing agreement. 

_Cookies_ : We may share information with advertising companies to serve You targeted advertisements, analytics providers, or social media providers.  This sharing is considered a “sale” under the California Consumer Privacy Act. You must be 16 years of age or older to use the Service. As a result, We do not sell personal information of consumers under 16 years of age.  The information is sourced from cookies/tags placed on Your device. The categories of information shared include:

  * Geolocation Information: Non-precise geolocation data based on Your IP address or other analytics tools.
  * Inferred Information: Inferences drawn from your online activities reflecting Your preferences, behavior, and interests.

Depending on your location, you may need to opt in/consent to the placement of these and other cookies or you may have the option to opt out of these and other cookies.  Please see the [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for additional information about controlling cookies.

In addition to the above cookie-related actions, California consumers may select the “ **Do Not Sell My Personal Information** ” link, which has been included on Our sites as a component of California Consumer Privacy Act compliance to block targeted advertising, analytics, and social media cookies upon Your request.  See “California Disclosures” below for additional information.

_Other Sharing_ : We may share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Our [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service), or as otherwise required by law enforcement or national security requirements. We may also disclose information when requested to comply with a court order, regulatory investigation, or governmental request.

_Sensitive/Protected Information_ : We do not currently collect or process sensitive, special, or protected information.  In the event We decide to collect sensitive, special, or protected categories of information (i.e., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual), We will first obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You if We intend such information to be disclosed to a third party or used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You through the exercise of an opt in choice.  You will have the ability to opt out at any time. 

_Nevada, United States, Residents_ : We **do not** sell Your personal information for monetary consideration as set forth in Nevada Senate Bill 220. If We change this practice in the future, We will obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You before taking any such action.  You can write to Us at Our [Help Center ](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653)to add Your email address to a “do not sell” list.  Please note that You are responsible for updating Us in the event that You need to change Your email address on file. 

_Mobile Devices_ : You may choose not to provide information related to Your mobile devices. Information on disabling device location permissions can generally be found in Your device settings or by contacting Your carrier or device manufacturer.

## RETENTION AND STORAGE

We retain Your personal information only as long as needed to provide You the Service and as required by applicable laws and regulations. Except as otherwise provided by this Policy, or when deleted or destroyed at Your request, We typically maintain certain personal information and communications for a period of two years as is common in the industry.  

We may keep the minimal necessary personal information about You after You have deactivated Your account for the period of time needed for Us to pursue legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with (and demonstrate compliance with) legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce Our agreements.  For example, We maintain:

  * transaction data for seven (7) years for financial reporting;
  * certain personal information on accounts that have been found to violate Service terms or policies to assist with fraud and abuse prevention and personal information obtained in relation to legal or regulatory requests for up to ten (10) years;
  * contact information for 90 days following transactions in the event of dispute.

Information submitted to or obtained via Our Service is maintained on secure servers and cloud platforms in the United States.

## SAFEGUARDING YOUR INFORMATION

We use the following security measures and technologies to protect Your personal information:

  * Physical access controls, including secured premises to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to personal information, and ensuring that off-site data centers and server facilities adhere to similar appropriate controls;
  * System access controls to prevent unauthorized access and use of personal information, which vary based on the nature of information processing, but may include: industry standard firewalls, authentication via hashed and salted passwords;
  * Data access controls to ensure personal information is accessible and manageable only by properly authorized staff, including restricted catalogue query and application access, need-to-know access restrictions, and restrictions on the personal information that can be read, copied, modified and/or removed;
  * Transmission controls, including encrypted data transfer over SSL and other controls to ensure that personal information cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization during electronic transmission or transport;
  * Input controls to ensure that any personal information is provided and edited by You or by Us at Your direction;
  * Data backups are taken on a regular basis, and are secured and encrypted;
  * Logical separation to ensure that personal information is only processed per the terms of this Privacy Policy and the privacy settings selected by You.
  * Despite Our efforts, no security measure can be absolute, and there can be no guarantee that Your personal information will not be accessed through malicious means, inadvertent disclosure, or mistake. If We are the source of a breach, We will contact You and describe the breach, along with Our mitigation actions. Where applicable, We will provide appropriate identity theft prevention and mitigation services at no cost to the affected person for not less than 12 months. 

## TRANSFER OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

Privacy and data protection laws and regulations and their associated transfer requirements vary by location (state, country and region).  We strive to comply with transfers of personal information under these laws and regulations by ensuring transfer is made under an appropriate legal basis.  We only transfer personal information to those parties that act as service providers or processors with respect to the Service We provide to You, with your consent, or under a legitimate interest or business, or commercial purpose, as described in this Policy.  We may also transfer personal information if required to do so by other applicable laws and regulations, including those related to criminal or civil matters.

Our technical infrastructure is located in the United States.  If you choose to use the Service, you agree to Our [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service) which states that Your personal information will be hosted within Our United States infrastructure and Your personal information is required to be transferred to the United States as a result.  

To the extent that We transfer Your personal information outside of Your country of residence, We rely on the following mechanisms to ensure the security of that information:

  * EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield
  * Data Processing Agreements
  * Model Clauses (EU standard contractual clauses)
  * EU Adequacy Decisions
  * Intercompany Data Transfer Agreement (among Our affiliates) 

In the event that We go through a business transfer such as a consolidation, merger, restructuring, acquisition, or sale of part or all of Our assets, We will obtain Your consent to the transfer of Your information as permitted by law and to the continued use of Your information by the recipient following the transfer so long as they comply with this Policy. 

## PERSONALLY-IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION SUBMITTED BY CHILDREN

The Service is not intended for use by children under 16 years of age in the United States. Please consult local laws for age restrictions in additional jurisdictions. IF YOU ARE UNDER THE MINIMUM AGE FOR YOUR JURISDICTION, DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE PROVIDER SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER. If We determine that personally-identifiable information of children under the minimum age has been collected, We will remove the information from the Service. If You are a parent or guardian and learn that a child under the minimum age has created an account, You may contact Us and request that the information be removed from the Service at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.  

## CALIFORNIA DISCLOSURES

_Right to Know About Personal Information Collected_

Please refer to the “Information Collected” and “Information Sharing and DIsclosure” sections above.

_Do Not Sell My Personal Information/Notice of Right to Opt-Out of Sale of Personal Information_

We allow targeting, performance, and social media cookies to be placed on Our sites by third parties for _other valuable_ _consideration_ for the purpose of targeted advertising by programmatic advertisers, analytics for Service performance reviews and improvements, and social media interactions, respectively.  These third parties use information from cookies, such as Your geolocation and browsing behavior to serve You personalized advertisements. We do not otherwise “sell” (as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act) any personal information.  If You are a California site visitor or user, then You must select the “Do Not Sell My Personal Information” link available on the Service to block (opt out of) all targeting, performance, and social media cookies from Our Service on Your device.  Opting out via the link will place a strictly necessary cookie on Your device to identify You in future interactions with Our Service so that targeting, performance, and social media cookies are not placed during those subsequent interactions. Since this action must be performed by a person using Your device, We do not conduct any identity verification with respect to Your exercise of this right. You may contact Us at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com for additional information about Your opt out rights.  Please see the [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for additional information about cookies on or related to Our Service and steps You can take with respect to those cookies.  

_Right to Know and Right to Delete_

You may submit a request for the categories and specific information that We have collected about you or a request that We delete any personal information about You that We have collected, subject to certain exceptions.  Refer to the “Your Right to Access, Alter, or Erase Your Personal Information” section below for information on submitting requests pursuant to Your Right to Know and Right to Delete.

_Information Submitted by Minors under 18 in California_

If You are a minor under the age of 18 residing in the State of California, United States, You have additional rights under California law. You may request removal of any information or content You posted while under the age of 18. We cannot ensure that removal of information You provided to the Service will be complete or comprehensive (i.e., information posted to public groups and forums that may be accessed by non-users) but it will be complete and comprehensive on Our part (i.e., user account information). In addition, if at any time You delete Your account, We will remove Your information from the Service.  Deletion and removal of information is subject to exceptions to maintain certain information as described in the “Retention and Storage” section of this Policy.

_Your California Privacy Rights (Shine the Light Law)_

We do not share personal information as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine The Light law”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes absent Your consent. If You are a California resident, You may request information about Our compliance with the Shine the Light law by contacting Us by email to privacy [at] discogs [dot] com or by sending a letter to Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403. Any such request must include "California Privacy Rights Request" in the first line of the description and include Your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that We are only required to respond to one request per user each year, and We are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address or mail address.

## NOTIFICATION AND OTHER PRIVACY PREFERENCES

We do not send spam and do not permit spam on or through Our Service. We comply with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 (US) and applicable international anti-spam regulations.  Portions of Our Service include account registration or opt in to receive emails. You may opt out of those portions at any time. Information about privacy and notification preferences within the Service, including opt in and opt out settings, can be found in Our [How To Adjust Account, Notification & Other Privacy Preferences](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360040252973-How-To-Adjust-Account-Notification-Other-Privacy-Preference) help document.  

## PUBLIC GROUPS & FORUMS

Information You post to the public areas of the Service (groups / forums / searchable catalogue) is not private, and is not protected under this Policy. Please exercise caution when disclosing Your information in these areas. You acknowledge that Other Users and the public, in general, not covered by this Policy will have access to Your public postings and We cannot be responsible for any subsequent use of personal information contained in Your public postings.

## ANALYTICS & DISPLAY ADVERTISING, COOKIES

We use cookies to provide the Service for functional reasons (such as personalisation), to measure performance (analytics), and for targeting online advertisements. Depending on Your location, You may have the ability to control certain cookie settings available on the Service.  Our Service will respect browser settings as “do not track,” “private,” or the like from supported browsers. Not allowing cookies may affect certain functionality of the Service. See Our [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for more information about how cookies are used with the Service.

## YOUR RIGHT TO ACCESS, ALTER, OR ERASE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

_Identity Verification and Authorized Agents_

If You submit a request to exercise Your rights under any privacy or data protection law and regulation, We will need to verify your identity prior to complying with Your request.  We verify requests by confirming the email address that sent the request is attached to a registered account on Our system. Deletion requests under the California Consumer Privacy Act include a second verification from the user sending the request.   If You do not have an account with Us the only data We collect and process is made available via cookies as allowed by law or regulation, which You can manage via Your “Cookie Settings” on the Service in applicable jurisdictions, or any email address and country (as applicable) that You provide when signing up for Our email subscriptions.

Your authorized agent may be able to make a request to exercise Your rights on Your behalf.  Please contact Us at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com to do so.

_Access_

You have a right to access Your personal information that We collect/process/store or personal information that We “sell” (as that term is defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act).  Other than Your IP address, geolocation, SSID, device information and operating system (collected when you access the Service), information collected via cookies (with your consent, as applicable), and information that You provide to Us in Your support requests, all personal information We collect from registered users can be found in Your user profile by reviewing:

  * Discogs.com accounts: Your [User Profile Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/user) and the additional settings noted in the menu on the left side of the page (i.e., Notification, Privacy, Buyer, Seller, etc.).
  * Nearmint.io accounts: Your [Account page](https://app.nearmint.io/account).
  * Other accounts: Your gear.discogs.com, films.discogs.com, books.discogs.com, comics.discogs.com, posters.discogs.com, and vinylhub.discogs.com Profile settings.
  * Cratediggers.discogs.com only collects Your email address and the country You entered when signing up to receive emails.

In addition,

  * We offer email subscription services available to both registered and non-registered users that collect only an email address provided directly by the user.
  * For those jurisdictions where We provide a cookie banner, cookie settings specific to Your device can be viewed via the “Cookie Settings” banner and links located on Our Service.

Additional information about privacy and notification preferences within the Service, including opt in and opt out settings, can be found in Our [How To Adjust Account, Notification & Other Privacy Preferences](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360040252973-How-To-Adjust-Account-Notification-Other-Privacy-Preference) help document. 

Personal information We “sell” (as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act) is limited to information generated by cookies and tags related to targeted advertising, analytics and social media.  See Our [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for more information.  We do not otherwise “sell” Your personal information.

You may also access Your personal information and how it is used and shared by completing the _Request Access of Data_ form in Our[ Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law.  Additional questions may be submitted to privacy [at] discogs [dot] com. 

_Accuracy, Rectification, Restriction, and Objection  _

We want to make sure that Your personal information is accurate and up to date.  If You would like to update personal information that You have previously provided to Us and are unable to do so using the [How To Adjust Account, Notification & Other Privacy Preferences](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360040252973-How-To-Adjust-Account-Notification-Other-Privacy-Preference) instructions, then please contact Us through Our [Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). In Your request, please make clear what information You would like to have changed, whether You would like to have Your personal information suppressed from Our catalogue or otherwise let Us know what limitations You would like to put on Our use of Your personal information that You have provided to Us. Some portions of Our Service may no longer be available if You request that We restrict processing or if You object to the processing of certain information.  We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. Additional questions may be submitted to privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.

_Erasure/Deletion_

You have a right to obtain erasure or deletion of the personal information You have provided to Us related to Your use of the Service. Exercising this right will result in closure of any account You have opened and removal of any items You have listed in your collection, wantlist or for sale in the Marketplace. In addition, exercising this right will impact certain functionality of the Service available to You online. If You request erasure or deletion, pursuant to the [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service), (i) Your user-generated content contributions will be anonymized by having the user name replaced by a generic term (i.e., "previous user1234" or simply "anonymous1234"), and (ii) We are entitled to continue using this anonymized user-generated content. We cannot guarantee that Your username as associated with any information You posted in public forums and discussions will be fully erased as Other Users have access to those portions of Our Service and may have used or republished such information, including Your username, subject to Our [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service), prior to the time of Your request. We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law or as set forth below. We may need to maintain certain information for longer than 30 days in order to carry out Our contractual obligations to You. For example, We provide support for transaction disputes for 90 days following the date of transaction. In addition, We may maintain minimal personal information on You for a reasonable period of time if You have violated the [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service) resulting in an account suspension or ban in order to protect other users or pursuant to any regulatory or legal exceptions allowing Us to maintain the information. You may submit a request for erasure or deletion by completing the _Request Erasure of Data_ form in Our [Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653).  Additional questions may be submitted to privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.

## YOUR PORTABILITY RIGHTS

You have a right to receive the personal information concerning You, which You have provided to Us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and You have the right to transmit those data points to another controller where Our processing is based on Your consent or any contract You have with Us and the processing is carried out by automated means. You may submit a request for portability by completing the _Request Portability of Data_ form in Our[ Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). Additional questions may be submitted to privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.

## NON-DISCRIMINATION POLICY

We do not discriminate against users of Our Service, whether You use the Service without incident or choose to exercise Your rights under any applicable laws or regulations.

## COMPLAINTS

If You believe that Your privacy rights have been breached or that Your personal information has been compromised as a result of using Our Service, please contact Us via the [Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to assisting with Your complaint. We will respond to Your complaint within 30 days of receipt if permitted by law and may request additional information from You to complete Our investigation.

You may also contact Our Data Protection Officer directly with any complaints at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

If You are a resident of the EU or EEA and feel that Your privacy has been infringed by Our Service or practices, You have the right to lodge a complaint directly with a supervisory authority in Your member state of residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement. The name and contact details of the Data Protection Authorities in the European Union can be found [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm). Our lead supervisory authority is [Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens (The Netherlands)](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/).

For complaints about content users or We have added to Our Service or items listed for sale through the marketplace that relate to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act or other copyright laws and regulations, please review the[ How Do I Report Copyright Infringement information](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009335133-How-Do-I-Report-Copyright-Infringement-) documentation.

## DISPUTE RESOLUTION

In the event that We are unable to resolve any complaint or dispute that You bring to Our attention, You may contact an independent dispute resolution body free of charge. We have chosen JAMS as Our independent recourse mechanism. You can file a claim with JAMS at the following website: [https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim). In some cases, You may be able to invoke binding arbitration. 

## GENERAL

We may amend this Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site and notifying You of material changes to the Policy along with an opportunity to opt in to changes that require Your consent by law or regulation or to opt out of any changes that decrease Your rights under this Policy. All non-material changes to Our terms are effective on the effective date of the Policy. We encourage You to review this Policy from time to time. By continuing to use the Service after non-material changes are effective, or after being notified of a material change, You will be deemed to have accepted the changes.

We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission in connection with Our Privacy Shield compliance.

## CONTACT US

You can contact Us about this Policy and Our practices via Our [Help Center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at privacy [at] discogs [dot] com.  

## **Discogs Privacy Policy effective through December 31, 2019  **

Your privacy is important to Us and this Policy represents Our commitment to care for Your personal information. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to the data We collect on Our websites, including [discogs.com](https://www.discogs.com/), applications, and through any associated service, including Application Program Interfaces (“APIs”), (collectively, the “Services”), provided to You by Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs) and its affiliates (“We”, “Our” “Us” or “Discogs”). Affiliates include Discogs B.V., Discogs G.K., and NearMint, LLC. It does not apply to data collected by or through any other online or offline sites, products, or services. When You (“You”, “Your”) use sites, products, or services other than Our Services, You are subject to those service providers’ policies. In addition, this Policy does not cover data You independently disclose to other users of the Services. Disclosure of data to buyers, sellers, or contributors, or other users (collectively, “Other Users”) outside of disclosure to Us should be discussed with those Other Users prior to providing such data.

**We comply with the the General Data Protection Regulation.**  Additional information about Our Data Protection Officer, information We collect, the purpose of collection and Your rights are provided in detail within this Policy.

**We comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework**  as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. We have certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view Our certification, please visit[ https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). See below for additional information on the types of information We collect, how We use it and to whom and when it is disclosed. We are liable for privacy violations committed by third parties to which it provides Your information as limited by Our contractual agreements with those third parties. All Personal Information received from the EU and Switzerland will be subject to the Privacy Shield. If You have a privacy-related complaint, please complete Our[ Privacy Complaint Form](https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QRXHH2C). Additional forms related to Your rights to access, erasure and portability can be found in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). You can also submit general privacy-related complaints or questions through the[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653).

## **Data Controller**

Personal Information provided to Us in connection with the Services or otherwise is controlled and processed by Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403, [privacy@discogs.com](mailto:privacy@discogs.com). Our EU representative is Discogs B.V., located at Korte Leidsedwarsstraat 12, 1017 RC Amsterdam, the Netherlands, [privacy@discogs.com](mailto:privacy@discogs.com).

## **Data Protection Officer**

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

## **Collection of Personal Information**

  * If You register to use the Services, We collect: Your username, email address, geolocation and IP address.
  * If You register to sell items using the Services, Discogs and Discogs Exclusives collect certain additional Personal Information: Your address and PayPal Account Name to allow You to engage in transactions and make use of the Services. If You use Our Shipping Labels Services, then We will also collect Your address.
  * If You elect the Discogs Payments Service, then You will need to provide additional information depending on whether You are a business or individual, which may include: name, date of birth, email address, phone number, company name, tax identification number, bank account information, government issued photo identification, and bank statement.  We also collect Your username, account creation date, IP address and email address for fraud review related to this Service.
  * When You purchase items using the Services, Discogs and Discogs Exclusives collect certain additional Personal Information: Your address. We do not collect or store any purchaser payment information, such as credit card information. Such information is provided directly to the seller by the purchaser with no interaction by or through Us. Depending on Your payment option selection, certain third parties may have access to such information (i.e., PayPal, Inc. or Adyen B.V.)
  * If You participate in the Discogs Self-Serve Advertising platform, then You will need to provide additional information, which may include: name, email address, address, phone number, and company name. This information is necessary for registration and payment within the platform. Please see the   [Discogs Self-Serve Advertising Payment Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360024763213-Discogs-Self-Serve-Advertising-Payment-Policy)   for additional information. 
  * If you register for [Cratediggers.com](https://cratediggers.com/), we collect your email address and country in order to provide you with relevant information about upcoming, local events.
  * If You send Us an email with a question or support issue, We collect: Your email address and other information You provide for the purpose of responding to Your question.
  * We keep Your Personal Information as long as necessary to provide the Services to You and as required by applicable laws and regulations.
  * If You decline to provide Us with any Personal Information as described above, certain features of the Services may be unavailable to You, such as selling or buying through the Marketplace.  Discogs Exclusives utilizes a guest checkout process and can be accessed without a user account.
  * We Ourselves generally do not collect Personal Information about You from any source other than You. However, We may receive information about Your location and Your device from Your carrier when You use the Services online or download Our app.

## **Information We Store When You Access the Services**

  * We use cookies and other technology to keep track of Your online interaction with Our site. Cookies may also provide information to Us about Your online interaction with other sites.
  * We may use cookies and similar technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information about Our users. The information collected allows Us to analyze how users use the Services. We also may use third-party advertising, and the companies providing this third-party advertising may use their own cookies. The collection and use of information by these companies is governed by the relevant third party's privacy policy and is not covered by this Policy. You have rights regarding Our use of cookies. Please see the[ Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) and  **Analytics & Display Advertising, Cookies** below for more information.
  * We retain Your Personal Information only as long as needed to provide You the Services. Except as otherwise provided by this Policy, or when deleted or destroyed at Your request, We typically maintain data and communications for a period of two years as is common in the industry. We may keep the minimal necessary data on You after You have deactivated Your account for the period of time needed for Us to pursue legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with (and demonstrate compliance with) legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce Our agreements.  For example, We maintain transaction data for seven (7) years for financial reporting and certain personal data on banned accounts for up to ten (10) years to assist with fraud and abuse prevention.

## **We use the Personal Information We collect to:**

  * Provide the requested Services, such as contributing information to the database or allowing for the purchase or sale of items through the site.
  * Personalize the Services for You and to communicate with You.
  * Send You emails from discogs.com, which may include newsletters, relationship and transactional messages, and marketing promotions. If You have previously consented to receive newsletters or other commercial emails, then You may opt out in Your notification preferences or from within the email messages themselves.
  * We do not participate in any automated decision making, such as profiling, with regards to the Services and Your Personal Information.

## **Disclosure**

  * We share information with third parties (processors) that act as an agent to perform tasks on Our behalf and under Our instructions. Examples include third parties that assist with payment processing (i.e., PayPal), shipping (i.e., USPS), or third parties that we contract with to send emails on Our behalf (i.e., MailChimp).

Please note that if You process payments through Discogs Payments, in the U.S., You will be contracting for this service directly with Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), and in the EU, You will be contracting for this service directly with Discogs B.V. sending emails on Our behalf, and fulfilling orders for merchandise purchased directly from Us (i.e., Discogs paraphernalia). In both cases, the payment processor working on Our behalf is Adyen B.V. This information is limited only to the information needed to perform the tasks.

Additional information about the processors We use to support delivery of Our Services is set forth at [Discogs Processors](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360004623634-Discogs-Processors).

  * We may share information with domestic and foreign affiliates controlled by Us, including Meta Zink Corporation, Discogs B.V., Discogs G.K., and NearMint, LLC. Our affiliates are subject to the terms of this Policy and follow the same privacy practices as Us. We are the primary Data Controller for Personal Information collected and processed through Our and Our affiliates’ sites and services. All sharing is subject to the Privacy Shield frameworks noted above.
  * We may share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Our terms of service, or as otherwise required by law enforcement or national security requirements. We may also disclose information when requested to comply with a court order, investigation, or governmental request.
  * We  **do not**  otherwise share Your information with any third parties.
  * We  **do not**  provide or sell email addresses or collection/wantlist data to any third party without Your consent.
  * We  **do no** t provide or sell Your Personal Information or any other information You have provided to Us to any third party for direct marketing or advertising purposes without Your consent.

## **Limiting the Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information**

We will provide You with notice in the event We intend to share Your information with a third party (other than as described above) or for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You. Prior to sharing such information, You will be provided with clear, conspicuous, and readily available mechanisms to opt in to such sharing, as required by applicable laws and regulations.

In the event We decide to collect sensitive information (i.e., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual), We will first obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You if We intend such information to be disclosed to a third party or used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You through the exercise of an opt-in choice.

Nevada, United States, Residents: We  **do not**  sell Your personal information for monetary consideration as set forth in Nevada Senate Bill 220. If We change this practice in the future, We will obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You before taking any such action.  You can write to Us at Our [support center ](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653)to add Your email address to a “do not sell” list.  Please note that You are responsible for updating Us in the event that You need to change Your email address on file.

You may choose not to allow cookies. Information on cookie settings can generally be found through the help feature of Your browser. If You block or otherwise disable Our cookies, certain Services may not be available. Please see the [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for additional information.

You may choose not to provide information related to Your mobile devices. Information on disabling device location permissions can generally be found in Your device settings or by contacting Your carrier or device manufacturer.

If You withdraw Your consent to this Policy (by closing Your account, if any), then You may not have access to certain Services, including the benefits of membership, buying and selling options. In certain cases, We may continue to process Your Personal Information, but only if We have a legal basis to do so.

## **Protection**

We use the following security measures and technologies to protect Your data:

  * Physical access controls, including secured premises to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to Personal Information, and ensuring that off-site data centers and server facilities adhere to similar appropriate controls;
  * System access controls to prevent unauthorized access and use of Personal Information, which vary based on the nature of information processing, but may include: industry standard firewalls, authentication via hashed and salted passwords;
  * Data access controls to ensure Personal Information is accessible and manageable only by properly authorized staff, including restricted database query and application access, need-to-know access restrictions, and restrictions on the Personal Information that can be read, copied, modified and/or removed;
  * Transmission controls, including encrypted data transfer over SSL and other controls to ensure that Personal Information cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization during electronic transmission or transport;
  * Input controls to ensure that any Personal Information is provided and edited by You or by Us at Your direction;
  * Data backups are taken on a regular bases, and are secured and encrypted;
  * Logical separation to ensure that Personal Information is only processed per the terms of this Privacy Policy and the privacy settings selected by You.
  * Despite Our efforts, no security measure can be absolute, and there can be no guarantee that Your Personal Information will not be accessed through malicious means, inadvertent disclosure, or mistake. If We are the source of a breach, We will contact You and describe the breach, along with Our mitigation actions. Where applicable, We will provide appropriate identity theft prevention and mitigation services at no cost to the affected person for not less than 12 months.

## **Personally-Identifiable Information Submitted by Children**

The Services are not intended for use by children under 13 years of age in the United States. Please consult local laws for age restrictions in additional jurisdictions. IF YOU ARE UNDER THE MINIMUM AGE FOR YOUR JURISDICTION, DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE PROVIDER SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER. If We determine that personally-identifiable information of children under the minimum age has been collected, We will remove the information from the Services. If You are a parent or guardian and learn that Your child under the minimum age has created an account, You may contact Us and request that the information be removed from the Services at [compliance@discogs.com](mailto:compliance@discogs.com).

## **Information Submitted by Minors under 18 in California**

If You are a minor under the age of 18 residing in the State of California, United States, You have additional rights under California law. You may request removal of any information or content You posted while under the age of 18. We cannot ensure that removal of information You provided to the Service will be complete or comprehensive (i.e., information posted to public groups and forums that may be accessed by non-users) but it will be complete and comprehensive on Our part (i.e., user account information). In addition, if at any time You delete Your account, We can guarantee complete removal of Your information from the Service.

## **Your California Privacy Rights**

We do not share personal information as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine The Light law”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes absent Your consent. If You are a California resident, You may request information about Our compliance with the Shine the Light law by contacting Us by email to privacy@discogs.com or by sending a letter to Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403. Any such request must include "California Privacy Rights Request" in the first line of the description and include Your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that We are only required to respond to one request per user each year, and We are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address or mail address.

## **Notification and other Privacy Preferences**

We don’t send spam and do not permit spam on Our sites. We comply with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 (US) and applicable international anti-spam regulations.

## **[Discogs.com](https://www.discogs.com/)  accounts:**

The settings pages for Your account allow You to manage the following information related to Your account:

  * [Notification Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/notifications): Choose how We communicate with You, including email messaging preferences.
  * [User Profile Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/user): Change Your personal information displayed in Your profile, including adding, rectifying, or removing incorrect data about You, and updating Your username and password.
  * [Privacy Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/privacy): Set privacy preferences for Your collection and wantlist, contact by other users and blocking users.
  * Additional settings controls are available in the[ menu](https://www.discogs.com/settings/user) for Collection, Applications, Developers, Buyer, Seller, and Labs.

You have the right to withdraw consent for various Services and related activities at any time and may do so by updating the settings noted above. You may also withdraw consent for marketing emails by selecting the “Unsubscribe From Emails” button at the bottom of the [Notification Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/notifications) page or unsubscribing from within the emails themselves.

## **[Cratediggers.com](https://cratediggers.com/)  accounts:**

If You sign up for a Cratediggers.com account, You are signing up to receive emails related to events and other industry information. In order to cease receiving emails and close Your Cratediggers.com account, You can unsubscribe via the link found at the bottom of the emails. 

## **[Gearogs.com](https://www.gearogs.com/), [Filmo.gs](https://www.filmo.gs/), [Bookogs.com](https://www.bookogs.com/), [Comicogs.com](https://www.comicogs.com/), [Posterogs.com](https://www.posterogs.com/) and [VinylHub.com](https://www.vinylhub.com/) accounts:**

The Settings page for Your account allows You to manage the following information related to Your account:

  * You can decide if You want others to browse and view your lists: Visited, Want to Visit, Collection, Wantlist or Following;
  * You can control email notifications related to your lists (Wantlist, Following), forum threads and submissions You’ve contributed to;
  * You can control your newsletter subscription settings.

You have the right to withdraw consent for various Services and related activities at any time and may do so by updating the settings noted above. You may also withdraw consent for marketing emails by unsubscribing from within the emails themselves.

## **[Exclusives.discogs.com](https://exclusives.discogs.com/):**

We do not currently provide an account registration process for Discogs Exclusives.  Buyers using this site will provide information through a guest checkout to conduct transactions.  Sellers work directly with Our staff regarding inventory. All communications will relate directly to transactions entered into by the parties.  You may contact Us directly regarding Your information related to Your use of this site via Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653).

## **Public Groups & Forums**

Information You post to the public areas of the Services (groups / forums / searchable database) is not private, and is not protected under this Policy. Please exercise caution when disclosing Your information in these areas. You acknowledge that others not covered by this Policy will have access to Your public postings and We cannot be responsible for any subsequent use of data contained in Your public postings.

## **Analytics & Display Advertising, Cookies**

  * We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to Our website. See Our [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334413-Cookie-and-Internet-Advertising-Policy) for more information.
  * The Google Analytics features We have implemented are based on Displayed Advertising (e.g., Remarketing). We use Remarketing with Google Analytics and Hivewyre to advertise online. You can review and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) on Google.
  * Third-party vendors, including Google, show Our ads on sites across the Internet.
  * Our Services will respect such browser settings as “do not track,” “private,” or the like from supported browsers. Opting out of receiving cookies or persisting cookies may affect certain functionality of the Services.

## **Your Right to Access, Alter, or Erase Your Personal Information**

You have a right to access Your Personal Information. All data We collect from You can be found in Your user profile by reviewing:

  * Discogs.com accounts: Your [User Profile Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/user) and the additional settings noted in the menu on the left side of the page (i.e., Notification, Privacy, Buyer, Seller, etc.).
  * All other accounts: Your [Gearogs.com Profile Settings](http://www.gearogs.com/my/settings), Your [Filmo.gs Profile Settings](http://www.filmo.gs/my/settings), Your [Bookogs.com Profile Settings](http://www.bookogs.com/my/settings), Your [Comicogs.com Profile Settings](http://www.comicogs.com/my/settings), Your [Posterogs.com Profile Settings](http://www.posterogs.com/my/settings), and Your [VinylHub.com Profile Settings](http://www.vinylhub.com/my/settings).
  * Discogs Exclusives does not provide for account registration. You can contact Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) regarding information You have provided in relation to transactions.

You may also access Your Personal Information and how it is used and shared by completing the Request Access of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. Discogs may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to releasing any information.

You may also access Your Personal Information and how it is used and shared by completing the Request Access of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to releasing any information.

We want to make sure that Your Personal Information is accurate and up to date.

If You would like to update Personal Information that You have previously provided to Us and are unable to do so through Your [User Profile Settings](https://www.discogs.com/settings/user) and the additional settings noted in the menu on the left side of the page (i.e., Notification, Privacy, Buyer, Seller, etc.) for Your Discogs.com account, or through Your Profile page for any other account as noted above, then please contact Us through Our [support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). In Your request, please make clear what information You would like to have changed, whether You would like to have Your Personal Information suppressed from Our database or otherwise let Us know what limitations You would like to put on Our use of Your Personal Information that You have provided to Us. We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law.

You have a right to obtain erasure of the Personal Information You have provided to Us related to Your use of the Services. Exercising this right will result in closure of any account You have opened and removal of any items You have listed for sale in the Marketplace. In addition, exercising this right will impact certain functionality of the Services available to You online. If You request erasure, pursuant to the [Terms of Service](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009334333-Terms-of-Service), (i) Your user-generated content contributions will be anonymized by having the user name replaced by a generic term (i.e., "previous user1234" or simply "user1234"), and (ii) We are entitled to continue using this anonymized user-generated content. We cannot guarantee that Your username as associated with any information You posted in public forums and discussions will be fully erased as users have access to those areas of Our site and may have used or republished such information, including Your username, prior to the time of Your request, subject to Our Terms of Service. We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law or as set forth below. We may need to maintain certain information for longer than 30 days in order to carry out Our contractual obligations to You. For example, We provide support for transaction disputes for 90 days following the date of transaction. In addition, We may maintain minimal data on You for a reasonable period of time if You have violated the Terms of Service resulting in an account ban in order to protect other users. You may submit a request for erasure by completing the Request Erasure of Data form in Our [support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to erasing Your Personal Information.

## **Your Portability Rights**

You have a right to receive the Personal Information concerning You, which You have provided to Us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and You have the right to transmit those data points to another controller where Our processing is based on Your consent or any contract You have with Us and the processing is carried out by automated means. You may submit a request for portability by completing the Request Portability of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to providing You with the requested information.

## **Complaints**

If You believe that Your privacy rights have been breached or that Your Personal Information has been compromised as a result of using Our Services, please contact Us via the [support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at privacy@discogs.com. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to assisting with Your complaint. We will respond to Your complaint within 30 days of receipt if permitted by law and may request additional information from You to complete Our investigation.

You may also contact Our Data Protection Officer directly with any complaints at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

If You are a resident of the EU or EEA and feel that Your privacy has been infringed by Our Services or practices, You have the right to lodge a complaint directly with a supervisory authority in Your member state of residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement. The name and contact details of the Data Protection Authorities in the European Union can be found [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm). Our lead supervisory authority is [Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens (The Netherlands)](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/).

For complaints related to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act or other copyright laws and regulations, please review the[ How Do I Report Copyright Infringement information](https://support.discogs.com/hc/articles/360009335133-How-Do-I-Report-Copyright-Infringement-) documentation.

## **Dispute Resolution**

In the event that We are unable to resolve any complaint or dispute that You bring to its attention, You may contact an independent dispute resolution body free of charge. We have chosen JAMS as its independent recourse mechanism. You can file a claim with JAMS at the following website: [https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim). In some cases, You may be able to invoke binding arbitration.

## **General**

We may amend this Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site and notifying You of material changes to the Policy along with an opportunity to opt-in to changes that require Your consent by law or regulation or to opt-out of any changes that decrease Your rights under this Policy. All non-material changes to Our terms are effective on the effective date of this Policy. We encourage You to review this Policy from time to time. By continuing to use the Services after non-material changes are effective, or after being notified of a material change, You will be deemed to have accepted the changes.

In the event that We go through a business transfer such as a consolidation, merger, restructuring, acquisition, or sale of part or all of Our assets, We will obtain Your consent to the transfer of Your information as permitted by law and to the continued use of Your information by the recipient following the transfer so long as they comply with this Policy.

We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission in connection with its Privacy Shield compliance.

## **Contact Us**

You can contact Us about this Policy via Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at [privacy@discogs.com](mailto:privacy@discogs.com).

## **NearMint Privacy Policy effective through December 31, 2019  **

Your (“You,” “Your”) privacy is important to us here at Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs) (“We,” “Us,” “Our”) and this Policy represents Our commitment to care for Your personal information. This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) applies to the data We collect on Our website, nearmint.io, and through any services associated with that site (“Services”) that We provide to You. Affiliates include Discogs B.V., Discogs G.K., and NearMint, LLC. This Policy does not apply to data collected by or through any other online or offline sites, products, or services. When You use sites, products, or services other than Our Services, You are subject to those service providers’ policies. In addition, this Policy does not cover data You independently disclose to other users of the Services. Disclosure of data to other users (“Other Users”) outside of disclosure to Us should be discussed with those Other Users prior to providing such data.

We comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) and other applicable international privacy laws and regulations. Additional information about Our Data Protection Officer, information We collect, the purpose of collection and Your rights are provided in detail within this Policy.

We comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. We have certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that We adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view Our certification, please visit[ https://www.privacyshield.gov/](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). See below for additional information on the types of information We collect, how We use it and to whom and when it is disclosed. We are liable for privacy violations committed by third parties to which We provide Your information as limited by Our contractual agreements with those third parties. All Personal Information received from the EU and Switzerland will be subject to the Privacy Shield and GDPR. If You have a privacy-related complaint, please complete Our[ Privacy Complaint Form](https://www.surveymonkey.com/r/QRXHH2C). Additional forms related to Your rights to access, erasure and portability can be found in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). You can also submit general privacy-related complaints or questions through the[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653).

## **DATA CONTROLLER**

Personal Information provided to Us in connection with the Services or otherwise is controlled and processed by Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403, privacy@discogs.com. Our EU representative is Discogs B.V., located at Korte Leidsedwarsstraat 12, 1017 RC Amsterdam, the Netherlands, privacy@discogs.com.

## **DATA PROTECTION OFFICER**

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

## **COLLECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

  * When You register to use the Services, We collect: Your username, email address, geolocation and IP address.
  * If You use Our Service to manage inventory for online marketplaces, We collect: Your user ID, API key and secret, the details We need for NearMint to stay connected with Your account(s).
  * If You send Us an email with a question or support issue, We collect: Your email address and other information You provide for the purpose of responding to Your question. This includes information submitted to Us to make a valid copyright claim, such as name and contact information.
  * We keep Your Personal Information as long as necessary to provide the Services to You and as required by applicable laws and regulations.
  * If You decline to provide Us with any Personal Information as described above, certain features of the Services will be unavailable to You, such as connecting to marketplaces and managing inventory on these marketplaces.
  * We Ourselves generally do not collect Personal Information about You from any source other than You. However, We may receive information about Your location and Your device from Your carrier when You use the Services online or on mobile devices.

## **INFORMATION WE STORE WHEN YOU ACCESS THE SERVICES**

  * We use cookies and other technology to keep track of Your online interaction with Our site. Cookies may also provide information to Us about Your online interaction with other sites.
  * We may use cookies and similar technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information about Our users. The information collected allows Us to analyze how users use the Services. You have rights regarding Our use of cookies. Please see the [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://nearmint.io/cookie-and-internet-advertising-policy/) and Analytics & Display Advertising, Cookies below for more information.
  * We retain Your Personal Information only as long as needed to provide You the Services. Except as otherwise provided by this Policy, or when deleted or destroyed at Your request, We typically maintain data and communications for a period of two years as is common in the industry. We may keep the minimal necessary data on You after You have deactivated Your account for the period of time needed for Us to pursue legitimate business interests, conduct audits, comply with (and demonstrate compliance with) legal or financial obligations, resolve disputes and enforce Our agreements.

## **WE USE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT TO:**

  * Provide the requested Services, such as centrally managing Your online inventory.
  * Personalize the Services for You and to communicate with You.
  * Send You emails, which may include newsletters, relationship and transactional messages, and marketing promotions. If You have previously consented to receive newsletters or other commercial emails, then You may opt out in Your notification preferences or from within the email messages themselves.
  * We do not participate in any automated decision making, such as profiling, with regards to the Services and Your Personal Information.

## **DISCLOSURE**

  * We share information with third parties (processors) that act as an agent to perform tasks on Our behalf and under Our instructions. Examples include third parties that we contract with to send emails on Our behalf (i.e., Mailgun). Additional information about the processors We use to support delivery of Our Services is set forth at [NearMint Processors](https://nearmint.io/nearmint-processors/).
    * We may share information with domestic and foreign affiliates controlled by Us, including Meta Zink Corporation, Discogs B.V., Discogs G.K., and NearMint, LLC. Our affiliates are subject to the terms of this Policy and follow the same privacy practices as Us. We are the primary Data Controller for Personal Information collected and processed through Our and Our affiliates’ sites and services. All sharing is subject to the Privacy Shield frameworks noted above, GDPR, other applicable international privacy and data laws and regulations, and an intercompany data processing agreement.
    * We may share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law enforcement or national security requirements. We may also disclose information when requested to comply with a court order, investigation, or governmental request.
    * We do not otherwise share Your information with any third parties.
    * We do not provide or sell email addresses or inventory data to any third party without Your consent.
  * We do not provide or sell Your Personal Information or any other information You have provided to Us to any third party for direct marketing or advertising purposes without Your consent.

## **LIMITING THE USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We will provide You with notice in the event We seek to share Your information with a third party (other than as described above) or for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You. Prior to sharing such information, You will be provided with clear, conspicuous, and readily available mechanisms to opt in to such sharing, as required by applicable laws and regulations.

In the event We decide to collect sensitive information (i.e., personal information specifying medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership or information specifying the sex life of the individual), We will first obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You if We intend such information to be disclosed to a third party or used for a purpose other than those for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by You through the exercise of an opt-in choice.

We  **do not**  sell Your personal information for monetary consideration. If We change this practice in the future, We will obtain affirmative express consent (opt in) from You if We intend to sell Your information for monetary consideration. You can contact Our [support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) if you require additional information on this topic.

We  **do**  allow cookies to be placed on some of Our sites by third parties for other valuable consideration, such as targeted advertising and analytics. Some jurisdictions require that We obtain Your consent prior to allowing cookies, while others do not. You may choose not to allow cookies at any time. Information on cookie settings can generally be found through the help feature of Your browser. If You block or otherwise disable Our cookies, certain Services may not be available. Please see the [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://nearmint.io/cookie-and-internet-advertising-policy/) for additional information.

You may choose not to provide information related to Your mobile devices. Information on disabling device location permissions can generally be found in Your device settings or by contacting Your carrier or device manufacturer.

If You withdraw Your consent to this Policy (by closing Your account), then You may not have access to certain Services, including the benefits of membership, inventory management and other options. In certain cases, We may continue to process Your Personal Information, but only if We have a legal basis to do so.

## **PROTECTION**

We use the following security measures and technologies to protect Your data:

  * Physical access controls, including secured premises to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to Personal Information, and ensuring that off-site data centers and server facilities adhere to similar appropriate controls;
  * System access controls to prevent unauthorized access and use of Personal Information, which vary based on the nature of information processing, but may include: industry standard firewalls, authentication via hashed and salted passwords;
  * Data access controls to ensure Personal Information is accessible and manageable only by properly authorized staff, including restricted database query and application access, need-to-know access restrictions, and restrictions on the Personal Information that can be read, copied, modified and/or removed;
  * Transmission controls, including encrypted data transfer over SSL and other controls to ensure that Personal Information cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization during electronic transmission or transport;
  * Input controls to ensure that any Personal Information is provided and edited by You or by Us at Your direction;
  * Data backups are taken on regular bases, and are secured and encrypted;
  * Logical separation to ensure that Personal Information is only processed per the terms of this Privacy Policy and the privacy settings selected by You.

Despite Our efforts, no security measure can be absolute, and there can be no guarantee that Your Personal Information will not be accessed through malicious means, inadvertent disclosure, or mistake. If We or one of Our processors is the source of a breach, We will contact You and describe the breach, along with Our mitigation actions. Where applicable, We will provide appropriate identity theft prevention and mitigation services at no cost to the affected person for not less than 12 months.

## **PERSONALLY-IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION SUBMITTED BY CHILDREN**

The Services are not intended for use by children under 18 years of age in the United States. Please consult local laws for age restrictions in additional jurisdictions. IF YOU ARE UNDER THE MINIMUM AGE FOR YOUR JURISDICTION, DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER. If We determine that personally-identifiable information of persons under the minimum age has been collected, We will remove the information from the Services. If You are a parent or guardian and learn that Your child under the minimum age has created an account, You may contact Us and request that the information be removed from the Services at compliance@discogs.com.

## **INFORMATION SUBMITTED BY MINORS UNDER 18 IN CALIFORNIA**

If You are a minor under the age of 18 residing in the State of California, United States, You have additional rights under California law. You may request removal of any information or content You posted while under the age of 18. We cannot ensure that removal of information You provided to the Service will be complete or comprehensive (i.e., information posted to public groups and forums that may be accessed by non-users) but it will be complete and comprehensive on Our part (i.e., user account information). In addition, if at any time You delete Your account, We can guarantee complete removal of Your information from the Service.

## **YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

We do not share personal information as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine The Light law”) with third parties for their direct marketing purposes absent Your consent. If You are a California resident, You may request information about Our compliance with the Shine the Light law by contacting Us by email to privacy@discogs.com or by sending a letter to Zink Media, LLC (d/b/a Discogs), PMB #323, 6663 SW Beaverton-Hillsdale Highway, Portland, Oregon, USA 97225-1403. Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include Your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that We are only required to respond to one request per user each year, and We are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this email address or mail address.

## **NOTIFICATION AND OTHER PRIVACY PREFERENCES**

The Account Settings page for Your account allow You to manage the following information related to Your account: Change Your personal information displayed in Your profile, including adding, rectifying, or removing incorrect data about You, and updating Your username and password.

We don’t send spam and do not permit spam on Our site. We comply with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 (US) and applicable international anti-spam regulations.

You have the right to withdraw consent for various Services and related activities at any time and may do so by updating the settings noted above. You may also withdraw consent for marketing emails by selecting the “Unsubscribe” button at the bottom of every email sent by us.

## **COOKIES**

  * We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) to optimize website performance. See Our [Cookie and Internet Advertising Policy](https://nearmint.io/cookie-and-internet-advertising-policy/) for more information.
  * Third-party vendors, including Google, show Our ads on sites across the Internet.
  * Our Services will respect such browser settings as “do not track,” “private,” or the like from supported browsers. Opting out of receiving cookies or persisting cookies may affect certain functionality of the Services.

## **YOUR RIGHT TO ACCESS, ALTER, OR ERASE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You have a right to access Your Personal Information. All data We collect from You can be found in Your user profile by reviewing Your Account Settings. You may also access Your Personal Information and how it is used and shared by completing the Request Access of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653).We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to releasing any information.

We want to make sure that Your Personal Information is accurate and up to date. If You would like to update Personal Information that You have previously provided to Us and are unable to do so through Your Account Settings, then please contact Us through Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). In Your request, please make clear what information You would like to have changed, whether You would like to have Your Personal Information suppressed from Our database or otherwise let Us know what limitations You would like to put on Our use of Your Personal Information that You have provided to Us. We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law.

You have a right to obtain erasure of the Personal Information You have provided to Us related to Your use of the Services. Exercising this right will result in closure of any account You have opened and erasure of any inventory you have listed in the Service. In addition, exercising this right will impact certain functionality of the Services available to You online. We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law or as set forth below. We may need to maintain certain information for longer than 30 days in order to carry out Our contractual obligations to You. For example, We provide support for transaction disputes for 90 days following the date of transaction. In addition, We may maintain minimal data on You for a reasonable period of time if You have violated the [Terms of Service](https://nearmint.io/terms-of-service/) resulting in an account ban in order to protect other users. You may submit a request for erasure by completing the Request Erasure of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to erasing Your Personal Information.

## **YOUR PORTABILITY RIGHTS**

You have a right to receive the Personal Information concerning You, which You have provided to Us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and You have the right to transmit those data points to another controller where Our processing is based on Your consent or any contract You have with Us and the processing is carried out by automated means. You may submit a request for portability by completing the Request Portability of Data form in Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653). We will comply with Your request within 30 days and if permitted by law. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to providing You with the requested information.

## **COMPLAINTS**

If You believe that Your privacy rights have been breached or that Your Personal Information has been compromised as a result of using Our Services, please contact Us via the[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at privacy@discogs.com. We may ask for additional information to confirm Your identity prior to assisting with Your complaint. We will respond to Your complaint within 30 days of receipt if permitted by law and may request additional information from You to complete Our investigation.

You may also contact Our Data Protection Officer directly with any complaints at dpo [at] discogs [dot] com.

If You are a resident of the EU or EEA and feel that Your privacy has been infringed by Our Services or practices, You have the right to lodge a complaint directly with a supervisory authority in Your member state of residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement. The name and contact details of the Data Protection Authorities in the European Union can be found[ here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).  Our lead supervisory authority is[ Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens (The Netherlands)](https://autoriteitpersoonsgegevens.nl/).

For complaints related to the Digital Millennium Copyright Act or other copyright laws and regulations, please review the[ How Do I Report Copyright Infringement information](https://support.discogs.com/hc/en-us/articles/360009335133-How-Do-I-Report-Copyright-Infringement-) documentation.  

## **DISPUTE RESOLUTION**

In the event that We are unable to resolve any complaint or dispute that You bring to its attention, You may contact an independent dispute resolution body free of charge. We have chosen JAMS as Our independent recourse mechanism. You can file a claim with JAMS at the following website: [https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim](https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim). In some cases, You may be able to invoke binding arbitration.

## **GENERAL**

We may amend this Policy at any time by posting the amended terms on this site and notifying You of material changes to the Policy along with an opportunity to opt-in to changes that require Your consent by law or regulation or to opt-out of any changes that decrease Your rights under this Policy. All non-material changes to Our terms are effective on the effective date of this Policy. We encourage You to review this Policy from time to time. By continuing to use the Services after non-material changes are effective, or after being notified of a material change, You will be deemed to have accepted the changes.

In the event that We go through a business transfer such as a consolidation, merger, restructuring, acquisition, or sale of part or all of Our assets, We will obtain Your consent to the transfer of Your information as permitted by law and to the continued use of Your information by the recipient following the transfer so long as they comply with this Policy.

We are subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission in connection with its Privacy Shield compliance.

## **CONTACT US**

You can contact Us about this Policy via Our[ support center](https://support.discogs.com/hc/requests/new?ticket_form_id=360000062653) or at [privacy@discogs.com](mailto:privacy@discogs.com).
